BU Records: Baylor Foundation, Inclusive: 1992-2003, Bulk: 1995-2000
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Baylor Foundation
Inclusive: 1992-2003, Bulk: 1995-2000
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/378
Baylor Foundation
2 document boxes
BU Records: Baylor Foundation records include information about the Baylor Foundation, including investment presentations, correspondence, and financial information.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
In 1995 the Baylor University Board of Regents approved changing the name of the Tryon Foundation to the Baylor Foundation. The Tryon Foundation was named after Baylor’s co-founder William M. Tryon and was used by the university for holding and distributing funds. It had been in existence since 1981. The Tryon Foundation, now Baylor Foundation is a non-profit organization with tax exemption status. In 1995 Baylor University endowment assets were transferred to the Baylor Foundation and a board of twelve directors was elected to manage the foundation funds. A CEO was chosen by the university as a paid employee to manage the foundation as well. The purpose of the Baylor Foundation was to accept endowment gifts for the university, hold legal title to those assets, and manage those assets.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Baylor Foundation is divided into three series: Minutes, Correspondence and Financial Records. The majority of the collection is Financial Records compromised of meeting presentations about Baylor Foundation investments. Many of the presentations are formatted as printed presentations with graphs depicting change in investments over time. The majority of the documents are from 1995 — 2000. The dates on the folders refer to when the documents within were produced and correspond with the financial records therein. Due to the nature of many of the financial presentations that show changes over time, the presentations include information about Baylor University accounts dating back to the 1980s. The collection also contains financial research in the form of news articles and presentations from financial management firms. Many of the documents show or mention the Baptist Foundation, who invested a portion of the Baylor Foundation’s assets. The Minutes series contains the bylaws, articles of incorporation, meeting agendas and meeting minutes. Although the Minute series includes content from 1995 — 2001 it does not include information from every meeting from those years. The majority of documents in this series are from 1998 — 2001. The Correspondence series contains one folder with memos and e-mails. Further correspondence is intermixed within the “Financial Documents” series, as the correspondence pertains directly to specific financial documents they are near.
Arrangement
The collection is currently arranged in three series; Minutes, Correspondence and Financial Records. The agendas and minutes within the Minutes series are arranged chronologically. The Financial Records series is arranged chronologically within each subject. Subjects include research, investments, endowment and Baptist Foundation.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/378. Acquired 2001-08-24
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baptist Foundation; Baylor Foundation; Baylor University -- History.; Baylor University -- Endowments.
Subjects
Baptist universities and colleges -- Texas -- Waco -- Finance.; Education, Higher -- Texas -- Waco -- Finance.; Educational fund raising -- Texas -- Waco.; Tryon Foundation; Universities and colleges -- Texas -- Waco -- Planning.
Genres
Correspondence.; Financial records.; Minutes (Records)
- Minutes, 1995-2003; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains bylaws, articles of incorporation, directories and meeting minutes. This series is in excellent condition. All but the “Directories” folder of this series is restricted.
  - Articles of Incorporations and Bylaws [RESTRICTED], 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Directories, 1998-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas [RESTRICTED], 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Agenda and Presentation [RESTRICTED], 1998 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Agenda and Presentation [RESTRICTED], 1999 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Agenda and Presentation [RESTRICTED], 1999 July 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Agenda and Presentation [RESTRICTED], 1999 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1995-2001; 2
  General condition: Good.
  This series includes correspondence, primarily e-mails discussing Baylor Foundation finances. This series is in excellent condition. This series is restricted.
  - Letters and Memos [RESTRICTED], 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Financial Records, 1992-2001; 3
  This series includes the Baylor Foundation financial records, investment research, and meeting presentations. The one unusual format in this series is a presentation printed on 8.5 x 11" transparency film for use on an overhead projector. This series is restricted. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Sesquicentennial Council of 150, Financial Resources and Fiscal Planning [RESTRICTED], 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fundraising and Investment Research [RESTRICTED], 1994-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Research, Cambridge Associates Inc. [RESTRICTED], 1996 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baptist Foundation Investment Research (1 of 2) [RESTRICTED], 1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baptist Foundation Investment Research (2 of 2) [RESTRICTED], 1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Investment of Financial Resources Presentation [RESTRICTED], 1998 October 9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Investment Research [RESTRICTED], 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Russell Company, Baylor Foundation Asset Allocation [RESTRICTED], 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Endowment Research [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Endowment Presentation [RESTRICTED], 1999 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Asset Allocation Presentation, Draft [RESTRICTED], 1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Research, Investment Monitoring Group [RESTRICTED], 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Baptist Foundation Background Information [RESTRICTED], 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Russell Company, Baptist Foundation Fund Analysis [RESTRICTED], 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Baylor University Fund with the Baptist Foundation, Performance Data [RESTRICTED], 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baptist Foundation Cumulative Report (1 of 3) [RESTRICTED], 2000 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Baptist Foundation Cumulative Report (2 of 3) [RESTRICTED], 2000 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Baptist Foundation Cumulative Report (3 of 3) [RESTRICTED], 2000 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 13)